# AREZOU SAKHIZADA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **Summary**

Fullstack Web Developer with almost 2 years of professional experience in a startup company focused in the Electric Utilities/EV's sector and part of a hands on learning position where I worked with a variety of modern day software tools that required me to read documentation, experiment new concepts, and collaborate with my teammates to solve daily problems.

## **Employment**

The Logit Group Inc.

Market Research Surveyor (Part-time)

London Ontario Dec. 2020 to Current

- Conduct market research through standardized phone interviews and virtual focus groups to accurately enter into the systems

Elocity Tech Inc.

Junior Software Developer

London/Toronto Ontario May 2020 to Nov. 2021

- Worked on both front-end/back-end development of EV charge point management system (CPMS)
- Using JEST I conducted automated, integration and unit testing
- Creating/modifying CRUD operation for web-based REST API's
- Used Figma to design/modify website design to make it more user friendly

Saputo Inc. & Shepherd Gourmet and Dairy

**Production/System Quality Assurance** 

St. Mary's Ontario May 2019 to Aug. 2019

- Kept track of daily cheese waste/delivery timings on Excel spreadsheets while running SQL commands on Oracle (DB) to update inventory counts

London Life/Canada Life
Junior Software Developer

London Ontario Sept. 2018 to Dec. 2018

- Collaborate and communicate with Senior Developers to identify software requirements
- Assisted development/maintenance of a custom Enterprise Resource Planning system (BYOPC)
- Design/develop a program that creates backup files in order to upgrade to Windows 10
- Code/test/packaged software to ensure strong functionality and optimization
- Provided on the phone tech-support to internal London Life employees
- Debugged/maintained software program files that were used to backup C drive files using batch scripting and VB.Net
- Updated the mainframe job tasks/job scheduling and generated (SAS) reports using Cobol and JCL
- Used JIRA/Confluence for documentation and archiving

### **Awards**

### Girl Develop It (GDI)Hackathon 3rd Place Winner

Nov. 2021

- Our diverse team of 8+ girls in UI/UX, fullstack web development, project management and QA, came in 3rd place in the 3 day virtual Girls Hackathon Competition for Canada/US after building a small Health Info Web App.

Fanshawe College · Deans Honor Roll

June 2020

Ismaili Community of London · 5 Years of Volunteering Achievement

Aug. 2015

Received a badge for volunteering for 5 consecutive years in my local community

## **Volunteering**

## Girl Develop It · Volunteer Mentor Canada/US

July 2022 to July 2022

- Code review mentor for the next Girls Virtual Hackathon , registration, stage management, setup communication and marketing through social media

### Fanshawe College · Iron Falcons Robotics

Sept. 2017 to Jan. 2018

- Bi-weekly meetups to discuss important dates/events, finding sponsors/adding new group members and assisting in building the robotics parts

Fanshawe College · Tutor

Dec. 2016 to May 2017

- Provided 2-hour sessions of 1-on-1 tutoring international students with English and C#/Java to previous semester students in the CPA/IWD programs

### **Contact**

 ■ arezousakhizada@gmail.com

**5196978241** 

♥ 4 Mohegan Crescent London, ON N5V 2X6 (Open to Remote)

in www.linkedin.com/in/arezou-sakhizada/

🗘 a-sakhizada

### **Education**

Lighthouse Labs - Fullstack Web Developer Bootcamp Mar. 2022 to May 2022

Fanshawe College of Applied Arts and Technology

Sept. 2016 to Jan. 2020

Advanced Diploma Computer Programmer Analyst

## Skills

### **LANGUAGES**

JavaScript HTML/CSS C#/C++

#### LIBRARIES

React.js jQuery/AJAX

#### **FRAMEWORKS**

Node.js/Express.js

### DATABASE

MongoDB/PostgreSQL

#### **TESTING**

JEST/MochaJS

### TOOLS/TECHNOLOGY

Git/Github

AWS/Azure

**VS Code** 

**Visual Studios** 

IntelliJ IDEA

Chrome DevTools

Google ML Kit

JIRA

Linux

Gitlab

Figma

COBOL/JCL

BitBucket

DevOps